Essex Company Photographs 6633 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- P 217.563-.573 -- Everett Mill; Essex Co. Bldg.; Mitchells Falls; miscellaneous photographs, 1897-1910 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Item 7: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Item 8: View of corner of Essex and Union Streets, 1910; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Lawrence, MA, June, 1910
  - Item 9: View of South side of Essex Street, 1909; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Item 10: View of Proposed St. line at SW corner Essex & Union Streets, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Everett Mill in background
  - Item 11: View of corner of Essex and Union Streets, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Lawrence, MA, Everett Mill at rear, 1910
- P 217.193-.247; P217.193.323 -- Plymouth Mills, Leffel Wheels + Gates; Butler's Wheel Case; Washington Mills; Atlantic Mills; Lawrence Gas Co.; Munro Felt Paper; miscellaneous photographs, 1895-1925 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: View of turbine/wheel outside of unidentified mill building, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: View of turbine/wheel outside of unidentified mill building, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: View of turbine/wheel outside of unidentified mill building, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: View of turbine/wheel outside of unidentified mill building, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: View of turbine/wheel outside of unidentified mill building, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: View of penstock under construction at Plymouth Mills, 1913; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
    August 28, 1913.
  - Item 7: View of South Canal Wasteway, 1906; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: View of the penstock over Spicket River, 1926; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 9: Exterior view showing worker standing beside penstock and turbine under construction, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 10: 26" L. H. Leffel Wheel Type F, 1923; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 11: U. S. Worsted Co. 30" L. H. McCormick Wheel, 1910; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
    September 28, 1910.
  - Item 12: U. S. Worsted Co. 30" L. H. McCormick Wheel, 1910; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 13: Interior view showing disassembled turbine/wheel, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 14: Monroe Felt & Paper Co. Wheel No. 1, 1907; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 15: Monroe Felt & Paper Co. Wheel No. 1, 1907; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 16: Monroe Felt & Paper Co. Wheel No. 1, 1907; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 17: Monroe Felt & Paper Co. Wheel No. 1, 1907; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 18: Monroe Felt & Paper Co. Wheel No. 1, 1907; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 19: Plymouth Mills turbine water wheels, 1913; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 20: Butler's 30" Hercules Wheel, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 21: Butler's 30" Hercules Wheel, 1898; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
    May 1898.
  - Item 22: Unidentified turbine/water wheel, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 23: Turbine for Lawrence Gas Company, 1899; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 24: Turbine for Lawrence Gas Company, 1899; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 25: Turbine for Lawrence Gas Company, 1899; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 26: Exterior view of Butler's wheel case, 1898; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 27: Exterior view of unidentified wheel, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 28: Exterior view showing Risdon wheel, 1903; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Atlantic Mills
  - Item 29: Head gate at Pacific Mills, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Race No. 2, Sept. 5, 1897 [Canal Head Gate].
  - Item 30: Plymouth Mills Wheel Room showing Allen's Dynamometer, 1913; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
    December 1913.
  - Item 31: Plymouth Mills Wheel Room showing Allen's Dynamometer, 1913; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 32: Plymouth Mills Wheel Room showing Allen's Dynamometer, 1913; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 33: Plymouth Mills Wheel Room showing Allen's Dynamometer, 1913; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 34: Exterior view showing man standing beside quarter turns for wheels #8, 9, 10, 11, at Washington Mills, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 35: Exterior view showing man standing with turbine outside of mill building, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 36: Exterior view showing man standing with turbine outside of mill building, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 37: Exterior view of unidentified turbine parts, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 38: Exterior view showing Butler's wheel case, 1898; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 39: Exterior view of Plymouth Mills quarter turn wheel No. 2, 1913; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 40: Exterior view showing wheels at Plymouth Mills, 1913; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 41: Exterior view showing wheels at Plymouth Mills, 1913; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 42: View of 59" Type "F" Leffel Wheel at Champion-International, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
    September 1925.
  - Item 43: View of 59" Type "F" Leffel Wheel at Champion-International, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 44: View of 59" Type "F" Leffel Wheel at Champion-International, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 45: View of 59" Type "F" Leffel Wheel at Champion-International, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 46: View of 59" Type "F" Leffel Wheel at Champion-International, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 47: View of 59" Type "F" Leffel Wheel at Champion-International, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 48: View of 59" Type "F" Leffel Wheel at Champion-International, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 49: View of Champion-International Co. Leffel wheels and gates, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 50: View of Champion-International Co. Leffel wheels and gates, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 51: View of Champion-International Co. 43" Type "F" Leffel wheel, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 52: View of Champion-International Co. 43" Type "F" Leffel wheel, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 53: View of Champion-International Co. 43" Type "F" Leffel wheel, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 54: View of Champion-International Co. 43" Type "F" Leffel wheel, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 55: View of Champion-International Co. 43" Type "F" Leffel wheel, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 56: View of penstock under construction at Plymouth Mills, 1913; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 4)
- P 217.555-.562 -- Durrant Square, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: View of Durant Square, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: View of Durant Square, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: View of Durant Square, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: View of Durant Square, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: View of Durant Square, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: View of Durant Square, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: View of Durant Square, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: View of Durant Square, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 5)
- P 217.523-.543 -- Uswoco Mills; Spicket Mill; Merrimac Paper Co., 1872-1911 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: View of Spicket River Bridge at Canal Street, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Looking down stream
  - Item 2: Exterior view - building canal, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Exterior view - building canal, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Exterior view - building canal, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: Exterior view - building canal, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: Exterior view - building canal, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: View of repairing break in South Canal, 1881; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
    At Merrimac Paper Co.'s penstock, August 1881
  - Item 8: View of Break in Canal Bank, 1872; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Merrimac Paper Co., when installing new penstock, 1872
  - Item 9: View of repairing break in South Canal, 1881; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 10: View of repairing break in South Canal, 1881; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 11: View of penstock, 1911; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Uswoco Mills [U.S. Worsted Co.] April 24, 1911
  - Item 12: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 13: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 14: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 15: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 16: View of weir extention, 1896; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
    E. Davis & Son
  - Item 17: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 18: View of penstock, 1911; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 19: View of penstock, 1911; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 20: View of penstock, 1911; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 21: View of penstock, 1911; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 6)
- P 217.613 -- Essex Company's Dam, Lawrence, Mass. (March 3, 1905), black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 1)
- P 217.98-.192 -- Mitchells Falls; Kimball's Island; Gauge #1, #2, #3, #4; Hawkes Brook; miscellaneous photographs, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 2)
- P 217.507 -- photo of a group of men (Fred Whittier, C.J. O'Reilly, Richard A. Hale); P 217.554 -- Essex Co. Office (1898) [2 copies], black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Group of men, 1898; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Fred Whittier, C.J. O'Reilly, Richard A. Hale
  - Item 2: Essex Company Office, 1898; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Copy 1.
  - Item 3: Essex Company Office, 1898; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Copy 2.
- P 217.324-.345 -- Spicket River (Hampshire St. Bridge; Short Street Bridge; Lawrence St. Bridge); miscellaneous photographs, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: View of storm damage to Park, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: View of storm damage to Park, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: View of storm damage to Park, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: View of Lawrence Reservoir, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: Unidentified view, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: Unidentified view, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: Unidentified view, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Looking East from Hampshire St. Marion Ave. on the Right, June 1897
  - Item 9: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Showing Bennington St. Bridge from Marion Ave., June 1897
  - Item 10: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 11: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Showing Playstead and Avenue from Bennington St., June 1897
  - Item 12: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Marion Ave. and Lawrence St. Bridge Looking Easterly from Bennington St., June 1897
  - Item 13: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Hampshire St. Bridge and Marion Ave. Looking Westerly, June 1897
  - Item 14: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Hampshire St. Bridge and Marion Ave. Looking Westerly, June, 1897
  - Item 15: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 16: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 17: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 18: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Short Street Bridge Looking S. Westerly, June, 1897
  - Item 19: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 20: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
    North Approach of Short St. Bridge Looking West, June 1897
  - Item 21: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Item 22: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Short St. Bridge Looking Easterly, June, 1897
- P 217.72.97 -- Spicket River; Hampshire St. Bridge; Merrimack Valley Country Club; miscellaneous photographs, 1895-1897 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Revere House, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Revere House, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: View of Merrimack Valley Country Club grounds, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: View of Merrimack Valley Country Club, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: View of Pine Street and School House, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: View of unidentified residence, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: View of unidentified residence, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: View of unidentified residence, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 9: View of unidentified residence, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 10: View of unidentified residence, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 11: View of unidentified church and school(?) building, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 12: View of Kingston Street shanty, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 13: Hampshire St. Bridge and approaches, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Looking Easterly at Spicket River, June 1897
  - Item 14: Hampshire St. Bridge and approaches, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 15: View of unidentified house, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 16: View of Bodwell House, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 17: Essex Company house, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Essex Company house, Bailey at Phillips St., Lawrence, MA
  - Item 18: Essex Company house, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 19: Essex Company house, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 20: Essex Company house, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 21: Essex Company house, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Essex Company house, Corner of Bailey & Phillips Streets, Lawrence, MA
  - Item 22: Essex Company house, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 23: Essex Company house, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Item 24: Essex Company house, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 5)
- 0033.67.2.464 -- Photo album contents, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: 1936 flood images, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Album of photographs of 1936 flood, plus loose photographs that appear to relate to placing a chimney in place. Presumed to be Essex Company images.
- Negatives, black and white photograph (Box 16, Folder 7)